Henry Y. Porter Theater Memorabilia Collection MS003
Digital Collections and Archives, Tufts University
- Artists and other celebrities; prints, photographs, and artifacts, 1722 -- 1990; 1880 -- 1920; MS003.001; 33.95 Linear Feet; 1 Volumes; 4 Digital Object(s)
  - Letters and photographs of various theatrical and opera personalities, 1843 -- 1983; MS003.001.059
    Files include correspondences, photographs, clippings and two unidentified daguerreotypes.
    - Letters concerning May Davenport Seymour, 1897 -- 1967; MS003.001.059.00001 (Box 59)
      Various correspondences between Henry Porter and Anne Seymour, and others regarding May Davenport Seymour and the Davenport family known in theatre and film including Fanny Davenport and Edgar L. Davenport.
    - Charlotte Cushman Lot, 1939 -- 1973; MS003.001.059.00002 (Box 59)
      Correspondences between Henry Porter and Mt. Auburn Cemetary regarding the upkeep of her grave. Also includes clippings and a stereoscopic of her home. See also box 110.
    - Letters by and about Margarete Arndt-Ober and care packaeges, 1945 -- 1950; MS003.001.059.00003 (Box 59)
      Correspondences between Henry Porter and Margarete Arndt-Ober regarding care packages he was sending to her in Germany after the war. Includes receipts of packages and clippings of her career.
    - Photos and letters of Olga Sapio, 1893 -- 1945; MS003.001.059.00004 (Box 59)
      Mostly photographs of Sapio as a child, growing up with her family. Also includes programs of her performances, clippings, some negatives and letters concerning her returning to the concert stage.
    - Unidentified daguerrotypes and tintype, 1843 -- 1956; MS003.001.059.00005 (Box 59)
      Two unidentified daguerreotypes, one of an elderly woman, one of a man with a child each in a leather frame. One unidentified tintype of a young girl.
    - RCA Victor clippings, photos and letters, 1968 -- 1978; MS003.001.059.00006 (Box 59)
      Clippings on the company, a photograph of the house where the first gram-o-phone was developed and a correspondence between Henry Porter and RCA regarding the changing of the RCA symbol.
    - Antonio Scotti photos and clippings, 1930 -- 1950; MS003.001.059.00007 (Box 59)
      Clippings and photographs.
    - Enrico Caruso photos and clippings, 1919 -- 1974; MS003.001.059.00008 (Box 59)
      Clippings and photographs of many of his roles. Also includes commemorative stamps and a letter signed by Caruso. See also box 110.
    - Geraldine Farrar clippings and photos, 1942 -- 1983; MS003.001.059.00009 (Box 59)
      Clippings and photographs of many of her roles, some signed. Includes some letters to Porter regarding sending help to Margarete Arndt-Ober and includes copies of Farrar's birth and death certificates. See also box 110.
    - Various programs, 1912 -- 1940; MS003.001.059.00010 (Box 59)
      Signed program of Luella Melius and a program from the Boston Theatre's production of The Trail of the Lonesome Pine. Also includes two illuminated prayers previously framed by Porter.
    - Herbert I. Jackson photos, clippings and letter, 1949 -- 1956; MS003.001.059.00011 (Box 59)
      Photographs and programs from productions he worked on. Also includes a letter from Jackson's daughter regarding his effects to be made available since his death.
  - Enrico Caruso, porcelain portrait bust, MS003.001.060.001 (Box 60)
    White, approx four inches high
  - Enrico Caruso, porcelain bust as "Dom Richa" in El Duca del Mantua, MS003.001.061.001 (Box 61)
    Painted, approx. four inches high.
  - Cartes de visite album, opera singers, 1880; MS003.001.063.001 (Box 63)
    Original period album. Most names on the back of each card.
  - Theatre Greats of the Past, cartes de visites and cabinet card albums of theatrical and opera personalities, unsigned, 1870 -- 1900; MS003.001.064.001 (Box 64)
    Three albums, one large (includes inventory), two small, one of them devoted to Clara Louise Kellogg (1842-1916); the other includes an inventory. Original albums with most names of personalities on back of cards.
  - Cabinet card album, Famous Stage Stars of the Past, 1900; MS003.001.065.001 (Box 65)
    Includes inventory.
  - Cabinet cards from old albums, actors, actresses and opera singers, 1900; MS003.001.066.001 (Box 66)
    Three files of cards, some with cartes de visites.
  - Cartes de visite from original albums, 1880; MS003.001.068.001 (Box 68)
    From albums, one file with an inventory.
  - Framed, autographed photo of Ellen Terry with Ellen Haviland, 1892; MS003.001.093.001 (Box 93)
    Frame is 17" x 20", photo is 9 1/2" x 11 1/2." It is possible that this picture belongs to the Arthur W. Row papers, although we were unable to confirm this.
  - Alice Nielsen's fan from "La Traviata", 1902; MS003.001.097.001 (Box 97)
    Black lace fan given to Alice Nielsen by Leonora Duse in 1902 at Naples, Italy. It was used by Alice Neilsen when she sang the role of Violetta in "Traviata" after three weeks coaching by Duse. Cabinet card of Eleonora Duse also included.
  - Three opera costume crowns, MS003.001.098.001 (Box 98)
    Three crowns, possibly used by Olive Fremstad (see MS 003/002-91:11). One with rhinestones, one with cameos and one of metallic vines.
  - Teacup, wedgewood plates, figurine, MS003.001.099.001 (Box 99)
    Unspecified items including two Wedgewood plates with the profile of JFK and Winston Churchill, a blue teacup and saucer with an opera(?) figure on it, a figurine with pigs and a grammophone, a silver goblet (probably used as a prop) and a plastic framed picture of Adelina Patti.
  - Letters, clippings, lithographs, engravings and photographs, 1722 -- 1980; MS003.001.110
    Leftover items from processing the collection. Not previously organized.
    - Playscript; The Wrong Package, 1906; MS003.001.110.00001; Griffith, Helen Sherman (Box 110)
      Copyright by Walter H. Baker and Co.
    - Group Portrait with Mary Scott, autographed, MS003.001.110.00002 (Box 110)
      Autographed by Mary Scott.
    - Lithographs of musical personalities, 1925; MS003.001.110.00003 (Box 110)
      Includes a souvenir picture of Lucy Marsh, soprano.
    - Engravings of various subjects, 1722 -- 1900; MS003.001.110.00004 (Box 110)
      Includes one of Walpole and one of Deputy John Ellis
    - Porter's letters, unorganized, 1960 -- 1980; MS003.001.110.00005 (Box 110)
    - Clippings, Charlotte Cushman, 1940; MS003.001.110.00006 (Box 110)
      See also box 59.
    - John McCormack, 1957; MS003.001.110.00007 (Box 110)
      Includes clippings, an 8x10 photo and cut out pictures from magazines.
    - Geraldine Farrar, 1919 -- 1967; MS003.001.110.00008 (Box 110)
      Includes clippings, two original photos, a copy of her death cerficate and last will and a program from a performance at Symphony Hall in 1919. See also box 59.
    - World Peace Jubilee, 1863 -- 1872; MS003.001.110.00009 (Box 110)
      Includes original programs and ticket stubs from the concerts, stereoscopes and cartes de visite of the Coliseum, a broadside from a concert by Camilla Urso (1863), and a cabinet card of Ebew Jordan. Also clippings of 20th C. commentary about the event.
    - Boston Opera House, 1909 -- 1958; MS003.001.110.00010 (Box 110)
      Photographs of tearing down the Boston Opera House as well as postcards of original building and photographs (and a cabinet card) of men associated with the facility - Henry Russell, and Eben D. Jordan Sr. and Jr.
    - Enrico Caruso souvenirs, 1910 -- 1951; MS003.001.110.00011 (Box 110)
      Includes 12 postcards of Caruso in various roles, and a souvenir booklet on Caruso published by the Museo Teatrale alla Scala (1951). See also box 59.
    - [Francis Scott Key and Fort McHenry Fla, 1960 -- 1968; MS003.001.110.012 (Box 110)
      First issue Francis Scott Key and Fort McHenry Flag envelopes; Francis Scott Key card.
  - Two leather daguerreotype cases, 1870; MS003.001.111.001 (Box 111)
    These are left over as the best examples of daguerreotype cases from the Porter Collection. Each has space for one insert.
  - Photographs, postcards and negatives of performers and singers, 1876 -- 1985; MS003.001.112
    - 20th c. conductors, tenor and actor, 1934; MS003.001.112.00001 (Box 112)
      Charles Hackett (8x10); Eugene Ormandy (8x10); Milton Silk (5x7) - signed. Guiseppe Creatore (8x10); Sigmond Romberg (8x10); Eugene Ormandy(8x10 and postcard) - unsigned.
    - Clippings and clipped images 20th c. film stars, 1955 -- 1985; MS003.001.112.00002 (Box 112)
    - Musicians, singers - photos or engravings with attached signatures, 1876 -- 1915; MS003.001.112.00003 (Box 112)
      Ale Bull; Anton Seidl; Eugen d'Albert; Mario Ancona; Max Alvary; Pasquale Briguoli; Italo Campanini; Ernest Nicolini; Francesco Tamaguo; Anna de Belocca; Etelka Gerster Gardini; Pauline Lucca; Sofia Scaldri-Lolli; Rosa Sucher; Emma Cecelia Thursby; Minna Peschka-Leutner; Guilia Grisi (engraving); Mlle Rosa Sontag (engraving); A. Dippel; Guiseppe Del Fuente; David Bispham; Maud Powell.
    - Various postcards of entertainers, 1910 -- 1940; MS003.001.112.00004 (Box 112)
      Some signed.
    - Booth Family clippings, 1958 -- 1969; MS003.001.112.00005 (Box 112)
    - Various postcards, royalty and literary figures, 1910; MS003.001.112.00006 (Box 112)
      Unsorted.
    - Various postcards, opera and theatre figures, 1910 -- 1937; MS003.001.112.00007 (Box 112)
    - Postcards of performers, signed, 1909 -- 1939; MS003.001.112.00008 (Box 112)
      Ruby Savage; Morris Hermann Nissen (2); Marcella Sembrich, Ada Crossley; A. Dippel (?); unidentified.
    - Negatives copied from prints, MS003.001.112.00009 (Box 112)
      Rachel as Phedre; Cushman as Romeo; Junius Brutus Booth; unidentified (3); Lillian Nordica (13); Davenport grave; Blanche (2); Thorpe.
    - Photos with enclosed signatures (opera singers), 1886 -- 1939; MS003.001.112.00010 (Box 112)
      Jean de Reszke; Edouard de Reszke; Frances Hodgson Burnett; Minnie Hank; Richard Bowers.
    - Opera figures, 5x7s, 1902 -- 1950; MS003.001.112.00011 (Box 112)
      John Vickers and Brigit Nilsson; Marcella Seimbrich; Pauline Donalda (signed); unidentifed (signed).
    - Autographed photo, 8x10, unidentified, 1905; MS003.001.112.00012 (Box 112)
      8x10 stuck to glass removed from frame. Very delicate. Woman in opera costume.
  - Red silk scarf, 1955; MS003.001.113.00001 (Box 113)
    Red silk scarf used by Ellen Beach Yaw while teaching (1955). Monogrammed with a "Y". Ellen Beach Yaw was an American soprano (1869-1947). (See picture in 33:107)
  - White tuxedo bow tie, MS003.001.113.00002 (Box 113)
    Unidentified.
  - Small woven purse, MS003.001.113.00003 (Box 113)
  - Parts of a Juliette costume; hat and bag with belt, 1955; MS003.001.114.001 (Box 114)
    A gift from Edith Mason Ragland 03/04/55. Mint green velvet with pearl detail.
  - Unautographed cabinet cards of composers and musicians in original album, 1890; MS003.001.115.001 (Box 115)
    Inventory available. 126 images.
  - Unautographed cartes de visite and cabinet cards of famous singers in original album, 1890; MS003.001.116.001 (Box 116)
    Inventory available. 180 images.
  - The Stage and its Stars; a gallery of historical dramatic illustration, issues 1-14, 1887 -- 1888; MS003.001.117.001 (Box 117)
    Edited by Howard Paul and George Gebbie. Includes photogravure-steel plates and minimal biographies which accompany the images.
  - The Stage and its Stars; a gallery of historical dramatic illustration, issues 15-28, 1887 -- 1888; MS003.001.118.001 (Box 118)
- Olive Fremstad letters, photographs, memorabilia, 1896 -- 1975; 1914 -- 1951; MS003.002; 1.0 Linear Feet; 1 Volumes
  This series includes original and facsimiled letters by and between OF and Maynard Manning (an avid Fremstad collector), Mary Watkins Cushing (Fremstad's secretary and biographer) and Henry Porter. The series also includes an original working manuscript and galley copy of The Rainbow Bridge, Cushing's book on Fremstad. There are also numerous photographic images of her famous roles including Salome and original photographs of her family, her home in Maine and her wedding. There are photographs of Maynard's collection of her costumes and a magnetic album of photos and clippings which has not been broken up. There is also a monogrammed handkerchief belonging to Fremstad and a number of crowns which could possibly have belonged to her.
  - Monogrammed handkerchief, 1930; MS003.002.089.001 (Box 89)
    White with white embroidery.
    Fremstad, Olive
  - Engraved leather scrapbook, 1903 -- 1914; MS003.002.090.001 (Box 90)
    Clippings inside. Given to Olive Fremstad from S.S. Halsted.
  - Photos, clippings and negatives of her roles, 1896 -- 1935; MS003.002.091.00001 (Box 91)
    Some autographed.
  - Photographs at Nawandyn, 1915; MS003.002.091.00002 (Box 91)
    Includes wedding pictures to Harry Brainard and pictures with Mary Watkins. Also includes some photographs of her roles, some autographed, and some snapshots of costumes she wore.
  - Larger photos of roles and portraits, 1930; MS003.002.091.00003 (Box 91)
    One autographed.
  - Porter's notes on Fremstad, MS003.002.091.00004 (Box 91)
    Handwritten notes about her career and Porter's connection with O.F.
  - Mary Watkins' notebook on trip to Europe with Fremstad, 1911; MS003.002.091.00005 (Box 91)
  - Letters from and about Fremstad, 1933 -- 1969; MS003.002.091.00006 (Box 91)
    Letters to Porter from Mary Watkins Cushing and to Porter from Fremstad. Includes some clippings.
  - Clippings from Opera News and various programs, 1904 -- 1955; MS003.002.091.00007 (Box 91)
  - Clippings, 1914 -- 1953; MS003.002.091.00008 (Box 91)
  - Clippings, 1907 -- 1936; MS003.002.091.00009 (Box 91)
  - Clippings and letter, 1907 -- 1975; MS003.002.091.00010 (Box 91)
    Letter from George L. Subotich about his interest in Fremstad's career.
  - Costume inventory, 1912 -- 1952; MS003.002.091.00011 (Box 91)
    Includes proofs of O.F. in the roles of Tosca and Isolde, clippings, Porters notes on roles of O.F., a letter from Mary Watkins Cushing to Maynard Morris about the state of some of O.F,'s belongings.
  - Biography for the National Cyclopedia of American Biography and clippings, 1960; MS003.002.091.00012 (Box 91)
    Includes Porter's notes on O.F.'s roles.
  - Original death certificate, 1951; MS003.002.091.00013 (Box 91)
  - Clippings of O.F. and Willa Cather, 1907 -- 1957; MS003.002.091.00014 (Box 91)
  - Photos from album, portraits and roles, MS003.002.091.00015 (Box 91)
  - Photos from album, large, portraits and roles, MS003.002.091.00016 (Box 91)
  - Clippings and descriptions of roles, 1903 -- 1914; MS003.002.092.00001 (Box 92)
  - Manuscript copy of The Rainbow Bridge, MS003.002.092.00002; Cushing, Mary Watkins (Box 92)
    Edited copy not in any order. Includes letter from O.F. to Maynard Morris(1957).
  - Extra typed pages, (from The Rainbow Bridge manuscript), MS003.002.092.00003 (Box 92)
    In no particular order.
  - The Rainbow Bridge (galley copy), 1954; MS003.002.092.00004; Cushing, Mary Watkins (Box 92)
    Also includes caption copy.
- Scrapbooks, playbills and programs, opera and theatrical personalities and performances, 1815 -- 1982; 1900 -- 1960; MS003.003; 6.9 Linear Feet
  This series contains bound scrapbooks of the lives of various entertainers, programs from the Metropolitan opera and the Boston Symphony Orchestra, and a number of playbills from local productions.
  This series is arranged as found.
  - Theatre Record and Scrapbook, 1896 -- 1900; MS003.003.062.00001 (Box 62)
    Unknown owner, collection of clipped playbills and first-hand musings of New York productions between 1896-1900.
  - Boston playbills, 1940-41 season, 1940 -- 1941; MS003.003.067.00001 (Box 67)
  - Boston playbills, 1941-42 season, 1941 -- 1942; MS003.003.067.00002 (Box 67)
  - Boston playbills, 1941-42 season, 1941 -- 1942; MS003.003.067.00003 (Box 67)
  - Boston playbills, 1941-42 season, 1941 -- 1942; MS003.003.067.00004 (Box 67)
  - Boston playbills, 1941-42 season, 1941 -- 1942; MS003.003.067.00005 (Box 67)
  - Boston playbills, 1941-42 season, 1941 -- 1942; MS003.003.067.00006 (Box 67)
  - Boston opera season, 1942; MS003.003.067.00007 (Box 67)
  - Boston playbills, 1942-43 season, 1942 -- 1943; MS003.003.067.00008 (Box 67)
  - Boston playbills, 1942-43 season, 1942 -- 1943; MS003.003.067.00009 (Box 67)
  - Boston playbills, 1943-44 season, 1943 -- 1944; MS003.003.067.00010 (Box 67)
  - Boston playbills, 1944-43 season, 1943 -- 1944; MS003.003.067.00011 (Box 67)
  - Boston playbills, 1943-44 season, 1943 -- 1944; MS003.003.067.00012 (Box 67)
  - Boston playbills, 1944-45 season, 1944 -- 1945; MS003.003.067.00013 (Box 67)
  - Boston playbills, 1944-45 season, 1944 -- 1945; MS003.003.067.00014 (Box 67)
  - Boston playbills, 1943-44 season, 1943 -- 1944; MS003.003.067.00015 (Box 67)
  - Boston playbills, 1959-60 season, 1959 -- 1960; MS003.003.067.00016 (Box 67)
  - Programs, MS003.003.067.00017 (Box 67)
  - Plays, foreign programs, British stage, 1950 -- 1956; MS003.003.067.00018 (Box 67)
  - Miscellaneous theatre programs, 1910 -- 1959; MS003.003.067.00019 (Box 67)
  - Opera news, 1977; MS003.003.067.00020 (Box 67)
  - Theatre/opera playbills and programs, 1900 -- 1916; MS003.003.067.00021 (Box 67)
  - Henry Y. Porter collection of autographed pictures and letters from scrapbook, MS003.003.067.00022 (Box 67)
  - Boston playbills, 1890 -- 1892; MS003.003.067.00023 (Box 67)
  - Metropolitan Opera repertoires, 1950 -- 1959; MS003.003.067.00024 (Box 67)
  - Metroplitan Opera rosters, 1942 -- 1960; MS003.003.067.00025 (Box 67)
  - Masragni Opera Guild, 1943-44 season, 1943 -- 1944; MS003.003.067.00026 (Box 67)
  - Souvenir Programs and Playbills, MS003.003.067.00027 (Box 67)
  - Madame Borghi Mamo clipping, Illustrated London News, 1855; MS003.003.067.00028 (Box 67)
  - Sarah Bernhardt, Le proces de Jeanne D'Arc, MS003.003.067.00029 (Box 67)
  - Houdini souvenir program, MS003.003.067.00030 (Box 67)
  - Victor Talking Machine Co. letters and documents, 1923 -- 1938; MS003.003.067.00031 (Box 67)
  - RCA/Victor articles and advertisments, 1952 -- 1977; MS003.003.067.00032 (Box 67)
  - Skedge Miller clippings and letters, 1957 -- 1968; MS003.003.067.00033 (Box 67)
  - Robert Stolz greeting cards and program, MS003.003.067.00034 (Box 67)
  - Sembrich Memorial Studio guides, MS003.003.067.00035 (Box 67)
  - [Marion Anderson, clippings], 1940 -- 1960; MS003.003.067.00036 (Box 67)
    Clippings.
  - [Ignacio Paderewski, clippings], 1940; MS003.003.067.00037 (Box 67)
  - Boston Theater Season, 1981 -- 1982; MS003.003.103.00001 (Box 103)
    Agnes of God; Side by Side by Sondheim; Children of a Lesser God; Othello; Mass Appeal; Mornings at Seven.
  - Met in Boston, 1981 -- 1982; MS003.003.103.00002 (Box 103)
  - Met in Boston, 1979; MS003.003.103.00003 (Box 103)
  - Shubert Theatre, Boston, playbills, 1949 -- 1962; MS003.003.103.00004 (Box 103)
  - Boston Opera House playbills, 1946 -- 1959; MS003.003.103.00005 (Box 103)
  - Wilbur Theatre, Boston, 1955 -- 1960; MS003.003.103.00006 (Box 103)
  - Plymouth Theatre, Boston, 1950; MS003.003.103.00007 (Box 103)
  - Out of town theatres, 1915 -- 1958; MS003.003.103.00008 (Box 103)
  - The new Locust Theatre, Philadelphia, 1959; MS003.003.103.00009 (Box 103)
  - The Charles Playhouse, Boston, 1950; MS003.003.103.00010 (Box 103)
  - The Forrest Theatre, Philadelphia, 1959; MS003.003.103.00011 (Box 103)
  - The Walnut Theatre, Philadelphia, 1959; MS003.003.103.00012 (Box 103)
  - The Erlanger Theatre, Phildelphia, 1959; MS003.003.103.00013 (Box 103)
  - Shubert Theatre, Philadelphia, 1959; MS003.003.103.00014 (Box 103)
  - Colonial Theatre, Boston, 1940 -- 1960; MS003.003.103.00015 (Box 103)
  - Colonial Theatre, Boston, 1940 -- 1960; MS003.003.103.00016 (Box 103)
  - Colonial Theatre, Boston, 1940 -- 1960; MS003.003.103.00017 (Box 103)
  - Various Boston theatres, 1949 -- 1971; MS003.003.103.00018 (Box 103)
  - Metropolitan Opera, 1970 -- 1971; MS003.003.103.00019 (Box 103)
  - Boston Symphony Orchestra program, 1973 -- 1974; MS003.003.103.00020 (Box 103)
  - The Wisdom of Eleanor Roosevelt, magazine publication, 1962; MS003.003.103.00021 (Box 103)
  - Boston Symphony Orchestra at Tanglewood program, 1974; MS003.003.103.00022 (Box 103)
  - The Metropolitan Boston Artscenter, souvenir program, 1959; MS003.003.103.00023 (Box 103)
  - Carnegie Hall, Diamond Jubilee program, 1966 -- 1967; MS003.003.103.00024 (Box 103)
  - San Francisco Opera, program, 1979; MS003.003.103.00025 (Box 103)
  - "The Spirit of '75", souvenir booklet., MS003.003.103.00026 (Box 103)
  - Boston Opera House programs, 1912 -- 1932; MS003.003.103.00027 (Box 103)
  - Boston Opera House, programs from opera seasons, 1909 -- 1916; MS003.003.103.00028 (Box 103)
  - Handel and Haydn Society, memorial program, 1884 -- 1885; MS003.003.103.00029 (Box 103)
  - Handel and Haydn Society Commemorative Record, 1815 -- 1903; MS003.003.103.00030 (Box 103)
  - Handel and Haydn Society, playbill, Chicago Civic Opera Co., playbills, 1883 -- 1920; MS003.003.103.00031 (Box 103)
  - Boston theatre playbills, 1917 -- 1920; MS003.003.103.00032 (Box 103)
  - Brahms, Op. 68, music guide, 1877; MS003.003.103.00033 (Box 103)
  - Scrapbook of photographs from Oberammergau, 1910; MS003.003.104.00001 (Box 104)
    A scrapbook containing over 250 snapshots of the village and people of Oberammergau, Germany around the time of the 1910 presentation of the Passion Play. Also includes some loose photos of actors who performed in the play, including Anton Lang.
  - Rosa and Carmela Ponselle, 1918 -- 1955; MS003.003.105.00001 (Box 105)
    Mostly clippings of Rosa's career. Includes some original photos of Rosa and her dog as well as a signed portrait of Carmela. Date is approximate
  - Scrapbook, 1933 -- 1934; MS003.003.105.00002 (Box 105)
    Mostly political clippings included.
  - Scrapbook, 1931 -- 1933; MS003.003.105.00003 (Box 105)
    Mostly business related clippings.
  - Scrapbook, 1924 -- 1931; MS003.003.105.00004 (Box 105)
    Mostly musical and opera personalities included like Lilli Lehmann and Wagner.
  - Scrapbook, 1931 -- 1935; MS003.003.105.00005 (Box 105)
    Musical, opera and theatrical personalities including E.H. Southern.
  - Scrapbook, 1935 -- 1937; MS003.003.105.00006 (Box 105)
    Musical and opera personalities including Antonio Scotti and Ernestine Schumann-Heink and George Gershwin.
  - Scrapbook, 1938 -- 1941; MS003.003.105.00007 (Box 105)
    Musical and opera personalities including Ernest Schelling and Feodor Chaliapin.
  - Scrapbook, 1941 -- 1943; MS003.003.105.00008 (Box 105)
    Musical and opera personalities including Ignace Jan Paderewski and Emma Calve.
  - Boston theatre and concert scrapbooks, clippings; also one undated scrapbook of royal figures, 1933 -- 1962; MS003.003.109.00001 (Box 109)
    Includes clippings, programmes, playbills and illustrated prints of Boston musical and theatrical activity between 1933-40. Also includes a scrapbook of royalty from the nineteenth century, which is undated. The pages from 1962 include clippings about contemporay famous figures.
  - Boston theatre and concert scrapbooks, 1922 -- 1933; MS003.003.109.00002 (Box 109)
    Includes clippings, programmes, playbills and illustrated prints of Boston musical and theatrical activity between 1922-33.
  - Playbill scrapbook, 1886 -- 1923; MS003.003.119.00001 (Box 119)
    Includes clippings from playbills and programs on various productions in Paris, New York, Boston, Washington and Baltimore. Some include clippings of the actor's pictures. Playbills have extensive list of the casts for each production.
  - Boston Opera Company second season, scrapbook, 1910 -- 1911; MS003.003.120.00001 (Box 120)
    Includes postcards, images, clippings, playbills; compiled by Porter's daughter?